Jonathan Gumero

(832) 775-3445 • jongumero@yahoo.com • linkedin.com/in/jongumero

Mobile iOS Developer

I am a dedicated Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in the design, coding, analysis, and testing of complex systems. Track record in collaborating with peers to create reliable software and align developments with both business and system requirements, Proven ability to deliver under tight timelines, as evidenced by the implementation of 6 detailed installation and testing procedures at Duke Energy, which reduced equipment downtime by 15%. My collaborative nature, combined with strong communication skills, positions me as a valuable team player.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Duke Energy • Raleigh, NC • Full-time

Jul 2022 - Present

Electrical Design Engineer

- I reduced design errors by 30% by managing and revising over 100 technical drawings in a \$20M Large Power Transformer project, leading to a more technically accurate product.
- I reduced equipment downtime by 15% by introducing 6 highly detailed installation and testing procedures, resulting in an annual company savings of \$240,000.
- I decreased breaker-related safety incidents by 25% by leading the full design change of 55 obsolete circuit breakers, resulting in enhanced overall nuclear plant reliability.
- I increased plant compliance by 10% by evaluating and revising over 20 calculation documents, ensuring the plant's strict adherence to industry standards.

U.S. Air Force • Oklahoma City, OK • Internship

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Software Engineer

- I achieved a 97% unit test success rate by collaborating in pairs with fellow engineers to develop and create new code in B-2 Bomber Control Logic, resulting in enhanced system reliability and alignment with military requirements.
- The unit tests boosted overall testing efficiency by 13% with the addition of 50+ unit test cases, leading to decreased debugging time for the B-2 Bomber control logic.
- I improved code efficiency by 8% compared to previous versions by testing and validating over 5000 lines of code, resulting in enhanced technological performance.
- I decreased real-time execution by 15% by automating the startup process for flight planning simulation software, resulting in a significant reduction in overall mission planning.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Texas A&M University • College Station, TX • GPA: 3.75

Aug 2018 - May 2022

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Skills: Agile Software Development, C#, Communication, C++, Python, Unit Testing, AI Prompting

Interests: Weight Lifting, Hiking, Fitness Coaching, Philosophy, World Travel